Guide to the Bitterroot Valley Photograph Album 1905-1925
Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, The University of Montana--Missoula
Bitterroot Valley Photograph Album
1905-1925
University of Montana, Mansfield Library, Archives and Special Collections The University of Montana—Missoula Missoula, MT 59812 406-243-2053 http://www.lib.umt.edu/asc library.archives@umontana.edu
Mss 678
0.2 linear feet
Photos of the Bitterroot Valley in Montana between 1905 and 1925, and two photos of St. Ignatius, Montana.
This collection consists primarily of photographs of the Bitterroot Valley in Montana between 1905 and 1925, including the Bitterroot Highway, the Club House at Charlo Heights, the Stevensville Mercantile, and Sleeping Child Hot Springs. Many of the photos were taken by J. W. Johnson, a photographer in Hamilton, Montana, a few are by Herman Schnitzmeyer who worked for the Northern Pacific Railway, and the remainder are not credited. The collection also includes two photos of St. Ignatius, Montana.
Researchers must use collection in accordance with the policies of Archives and Special Collections, the Maureen and Mike Mansfield Library, and The University of Montana--Missoula.
Custodial history unknown.
Acquisition information unknown.
This collection is indexed under the following headings in the online catalog. Researchers desiring materials about related topics, persons, or places should search the catalog using these headings.
Johnson, J. W. (John William), 1878-1957; Schnitzmeyer, Herman
Bitterroot River Valley (Mont.)--Photographs; Saint Ignatius (Mont.)--Photographs
Photograph albums--Montana--Bitterroot River Valley
Montana; Photographs
Photographers--Montana--Hamilton
- Scenic view with large sign reading "Entrance to the Bitter Root Valley", circa 1910 (Box-folder 1/1, Photo number 678.001)
- Bitterroot Highway, circa 1920 (Box-folder 1/2, Photo number 678.002)
- West Fork of Bitterroot River, circa 1920 (Box-folder 1/3, Photo number 678.003)
- Club House at Charlo Heights, designed by Frank Lloyd Wright, 1922 (Box-folder 1/4, Photo number 678-004)
- Fort Owen, Stevensville, Montana, undated (Box-folder 1/5, Photo number 678.005)
- Hamilton, Montana, tourist campground, circa 1920 (Box-folder 1/6, Photo number 678.006)
- Hell Rock, East Fork, Bitterrroot Valley, circa 1910 (Box-folder 1/7, Photo number 678.007)
- Automobile near Hell Rock, East Fork, Bitterroot Valley, 1920 (Box-folder 1/8, Photo number 678.008)
- Gathering by Ravalli, Montana train depot, circa 1912 (Box-folder 1/9, Photo number 678.009)
- Sleeping Child Hot Springs Hotel, circa 1920 (Box-folder 1/10, Photo number 678.010)
- Sleeping Child Hot Springs Bath House, circa 1920 (Box-folder 1/11, Photo number 678.011)
- Stevensville Mercantile, circa 1920 (Box-folder 1/12, Photo number 678.012)
- Victor, Montana Main Street, circa 1920 (Box-folder 1/13, Photo number 678.013)
- Big Horn Sheep carcass hung on tree Little West Fork of the Bitterroot, circa 1920 (Box-folder 1/14, Photo number 678.014)
- Duck, geese, and other bird carcasses from hunting day at Lake Como, circa 1920 (Box-folder 1/15, Photo number 678.015)
- St. Ignatius, banner above the crowd reads "Mission Valley Welcomes New Settlers", circa 1910 (Box-folder 1/16, Photo number 678.016)
- Farm Photographs, circa 1920 (Box-folder 1/17)
- Scenic Images, undated (Box-folder 1/18)
- Buildings, undated (Box-folder 1/19)
- People, undated (Box-folder 1/20)